Giovanni Canzio

Front-end developer and Usability Designer

Cell: +49 176 39937616 (DE)

+39 348 9508413 (IT)

Email: giovanni.canzio@gmail.com

URL: www.giovannicanzio.it

I deal with **users**, providing them **fitting UX** solutions, improving their web **Experience**.

My favourite triad is of course **HTML**, **CSS** and **Javascript**, starting point for further libraries and tools.

Linux (and *nix) is my ideal habitat, **command line** is discipline and clean separation between code and output. **Vim** and **git** enthusiast.



Experience

GRIN Verlag GmbH

Front-end Dev, UX Design - Munich, 2012-now

- Grin Solutions website: UX design, front-end coding, Responsive Design implementation
- Grin Solutions project maintainance, front-end development, bugfixing
- · GRIN website front-end coding, bugfixing and maintainance
- · Usability testing sessions with real users on internal projects
- Internal collaboration with <u>bilandia GmbH</u>: Grin Solutions customers' projects maintainance, social-media marketing products development (facebook tabs and games)
- · Cross-browser and cross-device testing and debugging

Promuovitalia S.p.A.

Front-end Dev, Drupal themes coder - Rome, 2010-2012

- · PSD slicing and coding for native CMS themes
- · Drupal Intranet portals
- Cross-browser and cross-device testing and debugging
- Accessibility validation

ITJ Consulting SRL

Frontend developer - Rome, 2008-2010

- · PSD slicing and coding for native CMS themes
- Joomla Portals
- Cross-browser and cross-device testing and debugging
- · Accessibility validation

Università Telematica Guglielmo Marconi

Frontend developer - Rome 2006-2008

- · Actionscript development for online tests and exams with SCORM tracing
- Front-end development for intranet and internet portals
- · Usability and accessibility testing and validation

Agenzia Romana SRL

Frontend developer - Rome 2005-2006

- front-end development on various projects
- Wireframing
- · Usability testing

Education

Istituto Europeo di Design (IED), Rome - 2005

Master (Advanced Study Program): Web Design & Strategy

Final project: www.sabinamater.it (offline now, viewable on web.archive.org)

University of Rome "La Sapienza" - 2004

Degree: Sociology

Specialization: Communication and Mass Media

Skills

Front-end development

- Fluent HTML5
- Fluent CSS3/Responsive Design
- · Good Javascript/jQuery
- Efficient mastery on cross browser/device issues

UX

- use case analisys
- · usability testing
- · wireframing and prototyping

Validation

- W3C
- Accessibility

Languages

- Italian native
- English fluent
- German basic (currently A2.1)

Main Tools

Development

• Agile (SCRUM)

- Vim and Sublime Text
- linux/unix command line
- git

UX

- Axure (wireframing and prototyping tool)
- XMind (mind-mapping tool)

Hobbies

Raspberry Pi, retrocomputing, Lomography, amateur musician, cuisine